Donald Sur Papers MS133
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Donald Sur Papers
1970 -- 1999
1965 -- 1999
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Sur, Donald
MS133
13.2 Linear Feet 10 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is not arranged.
Custodial History
Box 9 and 10 were added in March 2009 when found uncatalogued in the Special Collections ranges. Containing largely Slavery Documents material, two envelopes found separately were labeled accordingly and were added to box 9. These boxes were removed from Tisch 002 in January 2010 and placed in front of the first row of the DCA stacks.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains original musical compositions, concert programs, correspondence and manuscripts of the Korean-American composer and musicologist, Donald Sur.
Related Materials
MS006 T. J. Anderson papers. Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University, Medford, MA.
Biographical / Historical
Donald Sur (1935-1999) was a Korean-American composer and musicologist and a graduate of Harvard. Sur was born in Honolulu, Hawaii on February 1, 1935 to parents of Korean descent. His family moved to Los Angeles shortly after World War II. He completed his undergraduate studies at the University of California at Berkeley after transferring from UCLA. He completed graduate degrees at Princeton University and later at Harvard University in 1972 (PhD in composition). Sur is most well known for his composition the "Slavery Documents." In addition to musical composition, Sur also taught music courses at several universities in the Boston area, including Harvard, MIT, Tufts, Wellesley College and Boston University. He died of cancer on May 24, 1999 at the age of 64.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Greater Boston arts; Faculty research; Music--Manuscripts.; Sur, Donald
- Additional accessions, 1965 -- 1999; 1970 -- 1999; MS133.001; 13.2 Linear Feet
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  - Musical scores, 1980 -- 1989; MS133-001 (Box data_value_missing_48d993826152808a24346ed6d2c83cdf, Box 1)
    Open for research.
    Scope and Contents
    This box contains the following scores: The Unicorn & the Lady, Violin Concerto, A Neo-Platonic Epistle, Dampierre, and Tango.
  - Notebooks, 1975 -- 1985; MS133-002 (Box data_value_missing_96e0dc1ece0d7ea80350ad036d79b838, Box 2)
    This box contains notebooks with Sur's sheet music.
  - Notebooks and musical scores, 1965 -- 1980; MS133-003 (Box data_value_missing_96e0dc1ece0d7ea80350ad036d79b838, Box 3)
    This box contains Sur's notebooks from his time as a student at Harvard, as well as musical scores.
  - Unidentified notebooks, 1965 -- 1999; MS133-004 (Box data_value_missing_96e0dc1ece0d7ea80350ad036d79b838, Box 4)
  - Personal papers and musical scores, 1965 -- 1990; MS133-005 (Box data_value_missing_48d993826152808a24346ed6d2c83cdf, Box 5)
    This box contains Sur's musical scores: Satori on Park Avenue, Piano Fragments, Lacrimosa, and several others. Also included are Sur's personal correspondence, mail, financial papers, concert programs, and other papers.
  - Musical scores and annotations, 1980 -- 1999; MS133-006 (Box data_value_missing_8adff19712bd95046cc4a6d9f21218a0, Box 6)
    This box contains Sur's musical scores Khumdori Tansaeng, Prelude for Piano, Memory Fragments, Berceuse, Missa Tea for Two, Sonnet 97, Lacrimosa,Satori on Park Avenue, as well as music from other composers such as Beethoven and several unidentified manuscripts. Some annotations are in Korean.
  - Red Dust and other compositions, 1965 -- 1990; MS133-007 (Box data_value_missing_6c8f2e8700cffe8d8f8772690048db3a, Box 7)
  - Music by other composers and Sur's personal papers, 1965 -- 1990; MS133-008 (Box data_value_missing_96e0dc1ece0d7ea80350ad036d79b838, Box 8)
    This box contains music by other composers (mostly reproductions), Sur's personal papers, and other music.
  - Slavery Documents manuscripts, 1985 -- 1990; MS133-009 (Box data_value_missing_6c8f2e8700cffe8d8f8772690048db3a, Box 9)
  - Sheet music, 1965 -- 1999; MS133-010 (Box data_value_missing_6c8f2e8700cffe8d8f8772690048db3a, Box 10)